

New York (917) 346-2781 nicky.li92@gmail.com PORTFOLIO GITHUB LINKEDIN

SKILLS React, Redux, Ruby, Rails, AWS, Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, JBuilder, git

PROJECTS

ummblr(React, Redux, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, AWS S3, Webpack, Heroku, Jbuilder)live | github

A single-page web Tumblr clone where users can post and share multimedia content

- Integrated user contents into shared presentational components to be more dynamic and give a fresh experience to users every time.
- Integrated AWS into Rails backend for better scalability reducing load times and media queries.
- Built a custom modal React component, which conditionally renders based user actions to maintain an intuitive and seamless user experience.
- Executed full user authentication to persist session and utilized React Router to ensure validations and protection of user content.

GumBall Attack! (Javascript, HTML5 Canvas, Webpack)

live | github

An arcade type game that requires quick-reflexes to dodge bouncing gumballs

- Devised a collision-detection algorithm to dynamically handle and update multiple objects.
- Developed game using Object Oriented Programming (OOP) principles to delineate responsibilities in encapsulated classes for better management of errors and future features.
- Implemented Web Audio API to enhance game-play experience by linking sound effects to player inputs.

EXPERIENCE

Medical Assistant

Noah Scheinfeld MD

Oct 2014 - Feb 2019

- Collaborated with eClinicalWorks (EMR software) developers to improve UI, UX, and workflow.
- Trained new hires in our electronic medical records (EMR) software to efficiently manage patient care records and tasks.
- Proactively researched and presented time-saving resources for managing routine tasks to ensure work productivity and increased satisfaction from patients.

NYU Law Library

Technical Services

July 2011 - May 2013

- Coordinated communication between vendors and professors to build good relationships.
- Handled all technical and troubleshooting difficulties to prevent loss of data.

EDUCATION

App Academy (2019) - Web Development

- 1000-hour immersive full-stack web development intensive with <3% acceptance rate
- Topics include: TDD, scalability, algorithms, OOP, coding style, REST, security, single-page apps, and web development best practices

New York University (2010-2014) - BA in Biology